A basic rotation (also called elemental rotation)
 is a rotation about one of the axes of a 
Coordinate system. The following three 
basic rotation matrices rotate vectors by
 an angle θ about the x-, y-, or z-axis, 
in three dimensions, using the right-hand
 rule—which codifies their alternating signs.
 (The same matrices can also represent a
 clockwise rotation of the axes.)
rotation of the axes.)


For column vectors, each of these 
basic vector rotations appears 
counterclockwise when the axis about
 which they occur points toward the observer, 
the coordinate system is right-handed, 
and the angle θ is positive. 